本作品由Norm HALFCD Team倾情奉献\N感谢原作提供资源.仅供学习交流.严禁用于商业行为\N请自觉于下载后24小时内删除!如果喜欢本片,请购买正版!
更多精彩 尽在www.NormTeam.com
压制:鬼谷子  字幕:鬼谷子\NCompression:GV-Sir  Subtitles:GV-Sir
飞天大盗 第1季第4集
S01E04 Cops and Robbers
哦,老地方没怎么变,对吧?
Old place hasn't changed much,has it?
这是Samuel Richards
Samuel Richards.
- 我应该认识他吗? - 他抢劫银行
- Should I know him? - He robs banks.
- 然后? - 然后...
- And? - And...
你和我一起去逮住他
you and I together are going to catch him.
我想你认错人了
I think you have me confused with someone else.
你玩象棋吗,Michael?
Do you play chess,Michael?
我比较喜欢玩蛇爬梯子（一种棋盘游戏）.
I prefer snakes and ladders.
- 这是我兴之所在 - 真高兴
- It's my great passion. - I'm happy for you.
我的IQ是157
I've an IQ of 157.
所以一旦我有机会...
So when I get the chance to lock horns...
挫挫伟大的Mickey Bricks的锐气...
with the great Mickey Bricks...
这样的机会是绝对不能放过的
It's an opportunity too good to miss.
你似乎让我处于危险境地
It seems you have me at a disadvantage.
我曾在反诈骗组呆了19年
I was in the Fraud Squad for 19 years.
- 那么现在呢? - Moores银行安全部主管
- And now? - Head of Security at Moores Bank.
老警察成了银行安全部门的头儿
Ex-cop becomes Head of Security at bank.
性质不太一样啊
It's hardly original.
哦,两回事,不过,有利可图,是的
Original no,but lucrative,yes.
我想既然有百分之百的确信...
I find it very easy to negotiate my contract...
那签署合同不是件难事
with a 100% Conviction rate.
有创意
Impressive.
我可是放走了每个我见到的骗子...
I have left every grifter I have ever met...
就在我眼皮底下
in my wake.
包括Albert Stroller
Including Albert Stroller.
哦,你是Victor Maher
Victor Maher.
Albert提过我,对吧?
Albert's mentioned me,then?
提过一次.我不肯定我记得清不清楚
Once.I'm not sure if I recall the exact words.
说说看
Go on,paraphrase.
"一个不道德的无耻的 两面派混蛋"
"An unprincipled reprobate two-faced son of a bitch."
我真的很想Albert
I do miss Albert.
你朋友?
Friend of yours?
切牌?
Cut?
我不知道你还有这手
I didn't know you could do that.
你不知道我的东西多着呢,dannie
There's a lot of things you don't know about me.
例如?
Such as?
我可以告诉你 不过那样的话,我就得干掉你
I could tell you.But then I'd have to kill you.
那也值了
That might be worth it.
我们是打牌呢还是要调情?
Are we playing cards or flirting?
我想我们可以两样同时做
I thought we could do both.
哦,是的,这就是为什么你总也长不大
Yeah,well,that's why you'll never grow as a person.
不像Mickey是吗?
Unlike Mickey?
这是你的专业意见还是仅仅 出于你对他的迷恋?
Is that your professional opinion or is that just because you fancy him?
- 还玩不玩? - 庄家选?
- Game? - Dealer's choice?
当然
Of course.
剥猪猡（每输一局就得脱一件衣服的扑克游戏）
Strip poker.
Danny17岁的时候 他叔叔就叫他望风...
When he was 17,Danny's uncle used him as a lookout...
而他和他的同伙 则抢劫了Windsor的一家赌场
while he and his crew robbed a casino in Windsor.
干得非常漂亮,很专业 他们清场的时候...
Good job.Professional.They cleaned the place out...
连闭路电视带子都带走了
and they took the CCTV tapes with them.
不管怎样,上星期找到了其中了一盘带子...
Anyway,last week one of these tapes turns up...
Danny的叔叔早不干了...
and Danny's uncle's long gone...
但他其中的一个同伙想做这笔交易
but one of his crew wanted to make a deal.
我以前组里的一个朋友把它给我看了看
Old friend of mine in the squad showed it to me.
他知道Danny现在是个骗子 而且他征询了下我的意见
He knew that Danny was a grifter now,and he wanted my opinion.
我想这也正是你所要跟我说的
Which I assume you're about to share with me.
如果我把带子交给反抢劫组,Danny Blue就得进监狱
If I show that tape to Robbery,Danny Blue goes to prison.
而我帮了你,就能制止这一切的发生?
And by helping you I can stop that happening?
是只有你帮了我,才能制止这一切的发生
Only by helping me can you stop that from happening.
目前我们在Edinburgh,Liverpool,Birmingham和London都有分部
Now,we've got branches in Edinburgh,Liverpool,Birmingham,and London.
而Richards每个地方都干过了,除了伦敦
And Richards has hit every one of those except London.
他昨天晚上到的这儿
He arrived here last night.
他得知他想见的
He's about to find out that the alarms expert...
警报专家已经被捕了
he expected to meet has been arrested.
一个老同事的帮助
A favor from an old colleague.
所以他肯定得另外找个人代替
So he's gonna be looking for a replacement.
然后该你上场了
That's where you come in.
贼抓贼
Set a thief to catch a thief.
我,可不是贼
I am not a thief.
设想一下你伙伴可以免于牢狱之灾
Think of it as a way of stopping your pal from going to prison.
Danny现在已经长大了
Danny's a big boy now...
他能自己照顾自己
he can look after himself.
3个7
Three sevens.
同花顺
Nut straight.
我们不需要把...
We don't need to take the...
我是说,你不至于
I mean,you wouldn't.
愿赌服输,Danny
To the victor the spoils,Danny.
- 换个游戏? - 嘿,你个变态
- Fancy another game? - You're sick.
Albert在路上了
Albert's on his way...
只是在消磨时间
Just killing a bit of time.
Albert在去Eddie酒吧的路上
Albert's on his way to Eddie's Bar.
打分得改个礼拜了
The mark's going to be another week.
所以每个人放轻松
So everyone hang loose.
这并不难,Michael
It's not complicated,Michael.
你要么帮我抓住他
Either you help me catch him...
要么我就让danny好看
or I'll have Danny put away.
我得到他,你得到带子
When I've got him,you get the tape.
再多给我点资料
I'm going to need some more information.
到那儿找我
You can find me there.
我们必须把Danny送走
We have to send Danny away.
算了吧Albert.能逃多久?一个月,一年?
Come on,Albert.For how long?A month,a year?
你对付不了这家伙,Michael,他极其恶毒
You can't deal with this man,Michael,he's poisonous.
我们必须让Danny来选择
We have to give Danny the choice.
我讨厌被别人颐指气使
I don't like being manipulated.
Victor Maher是个变态 我了解他
Victor Maher is a freak of nature.I know him.
他才不在乎什么银行或者Danny
He doesn't care about the bank or Danny...
他只在乎游戏本身
it's all about the game.
他就喜欢找上欧洲的欺诈高手 然后胜过他们
He's thrilled at taking on the best grifters in Europe and out-grifting them.
例如Jimmy Cohen,Mitch Peters,还有Carl Taylor
Jimmy Cohen,Mitch Peters,and Carl Taylor.
你不可能斗得过他 逃不出他得掌心
You can't outsmart him, you can't outmaneuver him.
他对于我们的计谋一清二楚 甚至于超过我们所知
He knows every trick we do and more,besides.
我想你是认识了可怕的魔鬼
I do believe you have a bogeyman.
别去,Michael
Don't go there,Michael.
- 他已经赢了 - 怎么回事?
- He's already winning. - How so?
如果如我所想,他盯上了你
If he's studied you like I think he has...
那他就知道了你三个弱点
he knows that you have three weaknesses.
他会用他们来对付你
He'll use them against you.
3个弱点?
Three weaknesses?
忠诚
Loyalty...
你的狂妄自大
that extraordinary ego of yours...
以及对于被要求怎么做的疯狂仇恨
and a psychopathic hatred of being told what to do by anyone.
我亲眼看着我父亲循规蹈矩
I watched my father doing exactly what society told him to.
而我也看到正是这个责任毁了我父亲
And then I had to watch as that same sense of duty crushed him.
我知道
I know.
不管什么目的 Maher知道这一切
Whatever the origins,Maher knows about them.
他正利用Danny激起你的忠诚
He's using Danny right now to spark your loyalty.
而你的自负又让你面对这个挑战
Your ego is beginning to relish the challenge...
接受了他
of taking him on.
接下来,他会刺激你
He'll goad you next...
然后削弱你足以毁了你
then belittle you enough to suck you in.
别去干
Don't do it.
看,还有更容易的办法
Look,there's an easy way out of this.
我要去拿到那盘带子
I'll just get the tape.
打扰了,这是你的吗?
Excuse me.Is that yours?
谢谢
Thank you.
Michael你太让我失望了
Michael,you disappoint me.
你必须了解,我已经尝试过了
You must have known I'd try.
这当然 我只是没想到你会这么傻
Yes,of course.I just didn't expect you to be so clumsy.
现在,怎么办Michael?
Now,what's it gonna be,Michael?
我们接着玩儿,还是赶快办正事?
Are we to play more games or are you gonna do as you are told?
那么,交易
And so,the deal.
你会知道Richards将何时以及如何抢劫这家
You'll find out when and how Richards is gonna rob this bank.
如果他离奇得改变了主意
If by some strange chance he changes his mind...
那带子就会交到警察局
the tape goes to the police.
要是他扭到了脚踝
If he sprains his ankle...
或者他的腰啦,身体的其他部分啊
or his wrist or any other part of his anatomy...
这是你把他推向了坟墓
then you will drag him into the vault yourself.
带子会交到警察局
Or the tape will go to the police.
当他打开保险箱的时候...
When he opens the vault...
只有在他正在打开的时候
and only when he's opened the vault...
只有在你和我看着他打开的时候
and only when you and I have watched him open the vault...
你才能拿到带子
will you get the tape.
我怎么知道你没有拷贝?
And how do I know you haven't made a copy?
因为那样就证明了
Because that would suggest...
我已经考虑到
that I have considered the possibility...
你比我聪明的可能性
that you can outwit me.
这是不可能的
Which you haven't.
在这最后的演习之后 我唯一意识到的可能就是
After this last performance,the only possibility I would consider...
我高估了你
is that I have overestimated you.
所以,现在,乖乖的,好吗?给我抓住贼
So now,be a good boy,will you?Go catch my thief.
你听清楚了吗?
Are you still here?
如果要安慰你的话
If it's any consolation...
我也有个头
even I have a boss.
你看,Michael,迟早
You see,Michael,sooner or later...
所有人都得为某人服务
everybody has to serve someone.
即使你也不例外
Even you.
将军
Check.
到手了没有?
Did you get it?
他就等着我去
He was waiting for me.
那现在怎么办?
So what now?
接手Sam Richards
Work on Sam Richards.
我会做Maher所要求的 我们去跟其他们交代一下
I'll do what Maher wants.Let's brief the others.
Sam Richards现在已经干过moores银行四个分部了
Sam Richards has now hit four branches of Moores Bank.
我们有密报他打算抢伦敦的分公司
We got a tip-off he's due to hit the London branch.
我不明白
I don't get it.
- 什么时候开始我们开始抢银行了? - 不是我们.是Richards
- Since when do we rob banks? - We don't.Richards is going to.
那,内容是?
So what's the con?
不管怎样这都会发生 我们只是事后分杯羹
It's going to happen anyway.We just take a slice after the fact.
哦,怎么我听起来还是像抢银行
Well,that still sounds like robbing banks to me.
什么时候开始,我们问去哪里拿钱了??
Since when did we ask where a mark got his money?
如果他已经接受了这件事情 那会给他一个公平的游戏
If it's going down anyway,then it makes him fair game.
哦,我们成了附属品了,无论是之前,过程中,还是之后
Yeah,and it makes us accessories before,during,and after the fact.
厨房已经空了,伙计们,我们 需要点成绩,而且要快
The cupboard is bare.Guys,we need a score and we need it fast.
我同意Michael的意见
I'm with Michael.
好吧,那我们知道他多少?
Okay,so what do we know about him?
不多,除了他不喜欢银行
Not much,except that he seems to dislike banks.
谁喜欢呢?
Who doesn't?
那,怎么做?
So what's the in?
他需要一个警报专家
He needs an alarms expert.
我们让Ash做诱饵
We use Ash as the bait.
你对警报系统了解吗?
What do you know about alarms?
- 我无所不知 - 你无所不知?
- I know about everything. - You know about everything?
好吧,既然如此
Okay,if you know about everything...
卢森堡首都是哪里?
what's the capital of Luxembourg?
卢森堡城
Luxembourg City.
- 好,你太棒了 - 谢谢夸奖
- You're good,you're very good. - Thank you very much.
你别无聊了,Danny
You're not helping,Danny.
不要开始把矛头对准我,小妞 就因为你已经看过我裸体
Don't start having a go at me,girl,just because you've seen me naked.
别问了
Don't ask.
好了,这就是我们要干的
Okay,this is what we do.
Richards现在皇家旅馆
Richards is staying at the Royal Lodge Hotel.
Albert从那儿钓他上钩
Albert will hook him in from there.
一旦他联系上
Once he's made contact...
他把我作为当地的毒贩子介绍给他
he introduces him to me as a local fixer...
我再把他介绍给Ash
and I pass him on to Ash.
Danny和我做什么?
What about Danny and me?
你们两个机动,补空档
We keep you two floating,plug any gaps.
好了,来吧,干起来
Okay,come on,let's do it.
裸体?
Naked?
- 剥猪猡 - 是的
- Strip poker. - Right.
- 你吃醋了 - 没有
- You were jealous. - No,I wasn't.
- 才怪 - 真没有
- Yes,you were. - No.
我只是担心你让他吃亏
I was just concerned you may have been taking advantage of him.
当然
Of course you are.
你能帮我个忙吗?
Can you do something for me?
当然,如果你想的话,我现在就去拿牌
Yeah,I'll go and get the cards now if you like.
不,我要你
No,I need you to...
让Danny分神一会儿
keep Danny out of the way for a while.
这很重要 我过后再跟你解释
It's important.I'll explain why later.
他有麻烦了?
Is he in trouble?
只要让他保持忙碌就行了
Just keep him occupied.
- 好的 - 谢了
- Okay. - Thanks.
我不敢相信
I don't believe this.
英国银行税率多少?3.5%?
What is the Bank of England interest rate?3.5%?
他们已经对我的信用卡收了我10倍
They've charged me 10 times this...
这卡我一开始就不想要
for a credit card I didn't want in the first place.
这什么?
What's all this?
警报装置
Alarms.
- 我以为你了解 - 我是了解,只是有点生锈了（不记得了）
- I thought you knew about alarms. - I do.I'm just a bit rusty.
- 我们可是有时间限制的 - 我知道
- We're on a clock here. - I know.
机动?这算什么?
Floating?What's that all about?
你打算抱怨一整天?
Are you going to bitch all day?
Albert,不错,他来做诱饵
Albert,okay,he's the roper.
Ash来装配 Mickey,是局内人
Ash does the fixing.Mickey,inside man.
我呢?机动人员 对我来说,听起来一无是处
Me?I'm a floater.To me that sounds like a turd.
我们要成为核心人员,是不是,Danny?
And we do like to be center stage,don't we,Danny?
我有才能 与全世界分享是我的责任
I have a talent.It's my duty to share it with the world.
- 你想得真周到 - 嘿,我喜欢这份职业
- That's very thoughtful of you. - Hey,I love it.
所以,那又怎么样?
So what's wrong with that?
你告诉我你不喜欢吗?
You're telling me you don't?
- 这是达成一个目的的一条途径 - 什么目的?
- It's a means to an end. - What end?
有一天,攒够钱在加勒比海买个小地方 就这样
Saving enough money to buy a small place in the Caribbean one day.That's it.
你是说这只是一份职业?
So you're saying it's just a job to you?
我不是这个意思
I didn't say that.
那你喜欢它吗?
So you love it really?
这重要吗?
Is there any point to this?
是的,你知道,这纵容了我
Yes.You know,indulge me.
让我来告诉你 你干吗不告诉我关于你的事情?
I tell you what.Why don't you tell me about you?
哈罗,又见面了
Hello,again.
早餐的时候我们已经见过了
We met briefly at breakfast.
是的,我记得,不好意思
Yeah,I remember.Sorry.
- George Cooper - Sam Richards
- George Cooper. - Sam Richards.
- 让我请你喝一杯吧 - 苏格兰威士忌,谢谢
- Can I get you a drink? - Scotch.Thanks.
你早上看上去不太高兴
You look like a man who's had a tough morning.
我在等个人,但他临时爽约了
I was expecting someone,but they've gone AWOL.
- 有没有什么我能做的? - 哦不,恐怕不行
- Is there anything I can help you with? - No,I doubt it.
请记住:不存在任何问题
Just remember:There are no such things as problems...
只存在解决问题的机会
simply opportunities for solutions.
谢谢,我会试着记住它
Thanks.I'll try and remember it.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
好了,伙计.我喜欢所有的老一辈骗术家
Okay,mate.I love all the old cons.
你知道,他们在书中所写的那些
You know,stuff they wrote about in books...
二三十年代时候的东西
in the '20s and '30s.
例如Charles Ponzi,"黄色小子" Weil
People like Charles Ponzi,"Yellow Kid" Weil.
- Danny,你真是个罗曼蒂克老手 - 我说吧...
- Danny,you're an old romantic. - See...
我知道你对此不屑一顾
I knew you'd take the piss.
不,我没有.我发誓
No,I'm not.I promise.
我不知道,我只是总想试试身手
I don't know.I just always wanted to try one.
- 看看是什么样的感觉 - 是的,我理解
- See what it'd feel like. - Well,then.
你应该知道
You shall.
拿我来说吧,我干保险业
Take my game.Insurance.
去年我们声称
We had a claim last year...
他妈的肯定有室内工作
that I was damn certain was an inside job.
一个富丽堂皇的屋子里发生了盗窃 天衣无缝的保安系统
There was a burglary at a stately home.State-of-the-art security.
他们来去
They were in and gone...
抢走了珠宝,没有留下一点指纹
with the family jewels without so much as a footprint.
问题是,我们不仅需要一个警报专家
Trouble was,not only did we need an alarms man...
而且要是一个老手,告诉我们这个怎么做到的
but a crooked one to tell us how it was fixed.
你找到了吗?
Did you find one?
是的,幸运的是,我知道这么个人
Well,fortunately,I had a contact for that.
极其缺乏职业道德,但非常出色
Terribly unethical,but needs must and all that.
- 我再给你倒一杯? - 好的
- Can I get you another? - Yeah.
是的,Albert?带他过来
Yeah,Albert?Bring him in.
不,我不是故意的,别急
No,I meant to do that,don't worry.
你听得见吗?
Can you hear me?
我马上让它安静下来
I'll quiet it down for you.
什么?
What?
我和我的银行经理有个重要的会议 你能帮我照看一下狗吗?
那是条很贵重的狗.是你的吗?我愿出高价来买它
银行经理在贷款部给我打电话 我破产了!
Danny宝贝,干得漂亮
Danny boy,well done.
让我们离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
- 不好意思 - 什么事?
- Excuse me. - Yes?
- 你是不是掉了狗? - 是的
- Have you lost a dog? - Yes.
- 我想它可能在那家酒吧里 - 谢谢
- I think he might be in that pub. - Thank you.
这是Vincent Cole
This is Vincent Cole.
Vincent,这是Sam.Sam Richards
Vincent,this is Sam.Sam Richards.
绅士们,我无意冒犯 但我有种强烈的感觉
No offence,gentlemen,but I get the distinct impression...
我不会想听到接下来的对话
that I don't want to hear this conversation.
- 谢谢,George - 我的荣幸
- Thank you,George. - My very great pleasure.
George告诉我,你认得些人能帮我的忙
George tells me you have contacts in a field that I need help with.
- 那方面的? - 警报系统
- Which is? - Alarm systems.
你要的帮助是什么?
And what kind of help are you looking for?
- 这个重要吗? - 如果你直说了,这个就不重要
- Does it matter? - Lf you're straight up,no.
如果你是条子,我就需要听听你的解释
But if you're a cop,I need to hear you say the words...
这样,我被捕的时候 能为这个诱捕辩护
so I can plead entrapment when I'm arrested.
好了,我还有其他活儿要干
Okay,I have other things to do.
对不起
Sorry.
咖啡,谢谢
Coffee,thanks.
我正计划抢个银行
I'm planning to rob a bank.
都计划好了才想起要个搞定警报的?
And a bell man is an afterthought?
我被放鸽子了
I've been let down.
我自己可以进入银行
I can get into the bank.
我可以解决外面的保安系统,一路到保险箱
I can deal with the outer security until I get to the vault.
然后,我就需要帮助
That's where I need help.
这是带有视网膜扫描的Locheim系统
It's a Locheim system with retinal scan.
这需要一个专业人员
That needs a specialist.
本来我有人可以搞定这个,但他昨晚被捕了
I had a guy lined up,but he was arrested last night.
- 你能不能绕过这个? - 不行
- Can you bypass it? - No.
唯一能够绕过这个安全系统的只有Victor Maher
The only one with the security override is Victor Maher.
他是安全部门的头儿
The Head of Security.
好吧,那你打算什么时候干?
Okay,so when are you going in?
- 明晚 - 你的
- Tomorrow night. - Here you go,pal.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么?你能助我一臂之力吗?
So?Can you help?
不能
No.
但我认识一个人可以
But I know a man who can.
这个小菜一碟
It's a piece of cake.
你黑进它的视网膜扫描系统,然后改变它的设置
You hack into the retina scans and reprogram new settings.
新设置是什么?
What are these new settings?
你用自己的视网膜扫描,取代他们的
You take your own scanner,replace their retinal scans with your own.
我可以给你这个软件,并在过程中知道你
I can give you the software and talk you through the process.
不管怎样,记得两边的扫描
Whatever you do,remember to wipe both scans...
都要在你离开前抹掉
on the computer memory before you leave...
否则,就好像你把自己的指纹留在那
otherwise it's like leaving your fingerprints behind.
等等.两边的扫描?
Hang on.Both scans?
这个Locheim系统在Moores银行刚刚更新过
The Locheim's been updated at Moores.
这是一个双重扫描,要两个人,八英尺远同时进行
It's a double scan,two people,eight feet apart.
- 你有多少人? - 一个
- How many in your crew? - One.
- 你单干? - 我一向这样
- You're doing this on your own? - That's how I work.
这个扫描系统是最起码的
The scan's the least of your worries.
你甚至于连血汗钱也拿不出来
You won't even be able to carry the bleeding money out.
我不拿钱
I won't be taking any money out.
我父亲吞枪的时候,是47岁
My dad was 47 when he took a shotgun...
放在他的下巴下面 然后扣动了扳机
placed it under his chin and pulled the trigger.
他继承我祖父的事业 经营一个小型钻石切割公司
He ran a small diamond-cutting business started by my great-grandfather.
我父亲接过公司的时候
By the time Dad took over...
许多大公司都在买新机器
bigger companies were buying new machines...
做的更快,更便宜
making stones quicker,cheaper.
于是他借了笔款子以维持经营
So he took out a loan to keep afloat.
当银行催他还款的时候
When the bank called the loan in...
他觉得他令整个家族失望
he felt he let down his entire family.
他羞愧的无法面对我们
He was too ashamed to face us.
是Moores银行吗?
Moores Bank?
他们是毒瘤
They're a cancer.
- 地方恶霸 - 怎么?所以你要报复?
- Playground bullies. - What?So this is revenge?
你知道,亲眼看着自己父亲死是什么感受吗?
Have you any idea what it's like to watch your father die?
眼睁睁看着整个家
Watch your whole family...
你熟悉和深爱的刹那间消失
everything you've ever known and loved disintegrate in a second?
他只想本本分分的,你懂吗?
All he ever wanted to do was play it straight,you know?
循规蹈矩的
Toe the line.
我知道这听上去有点蠢
I know this sounds stupid...
但这个与钱无关
but this isn't about the money.
继续说
Go on.
20年代的时候,我祖父买了块石头
In the '20s,my grandfather bought a stone.
还未经雕琢
Still uncut...
但当时仍价值25万镑
but even then it must have been worth 250,000.
银行用它来低偿了我父亲的债
The bank took it to recoup my dad's loan.
但却并没有把它进行拍卖
But instead of putting it up for auction...
而是占为己有,一笔勾销了债务
they kept it for themselves and wrote off the loan.
而我们的债务是4万镑
That loan was 40,000.
现在,我已经拿回了他们偷走的每一分
I've taken back every penny that they stole...
并尽我所能的大肆破坏
and caused as much damage as I could in the process.
但现在,我要拿回钻石
But now I'm gonna get the diamond.
就这样.然后走人
Then that's it.Then it's over.
保险箱里面就是这个?
And that's what's in the vault?
是的.但明天,他们就会换地方
Yeah.But they're moving it the day after tomorrow.
这就是为什么我迫不及待现在就要干
That's why I have to do this now.
除非,你所说的 他们警报系统已经更新是真的
Only,if what you say about them updating the alarm is true...
我就不能单干了
I can't do it on my own.
你知道,亲眼看着自己父亲死是什么感受吗?
Have you any idea what it's like to watch your father die?
眼睁睁看着整个家
Watch your whole family...
你所熟悉和深爱的刹那间消失
everything you've ever known and loved disintegrate in a second?
我父亲准时工作,吃饭,睡觉
My dad worked,ate,and slept.
纳税,循规蹈矩
Paid his taxes on time,toed the line.
他唯一的梦想就是好好退休
The only dream he had was retiring.
他一直工作到死 他60岁生日前三天
Worked himself to death three days before his 60th birthday.
每个人都得服从于某人
Everybody has to serve someone.
即使是你
Even you.
哦,我的天哪,你接得住吗?
Oh,my God,can you take a chip?
- 来吧 - 接住咯
- Come on. - Bingo.
嗨
Hello.
你之前结过婚,对吧?
You were married before this,right?
这就是为什么我会过现在这种生活 他是个不起眼的骗子
That's how I got into the life.He was a smalltime hustler.
我扮演妓女,找猎物
I'd play a whore,pick up a mark...
Jake就冲进来 以一个生气的皮条客或男朋友的身份
Jake would burst in as the irate pimp or boyfriend...
- 然后以他们的妻子相要挟 - 很漂亮,不是吗?
- and threaten to tell their wives. - Classy,isn't it?
我想,我们会有未来
I thought we were building a future.
然后,五年前
Then five years ago...
他卷跑了我们所有的钱,跑得无影无踪
he cleared out all our savings and he disappeared.
你那之后见过他吗?
You ever seen him since?
你想他吗?
Do you miss him?
当然,有一段时间,是的
Of course I did for a while,yeah...
但不会了,再也不会了
but no,not anymore.
我甚至于不再为此生气 生活就这么回事
I'm not even angry anymore.Things are what they are.
那Mickey是怎么卷进来的?
So where does Mickey fit into all this?
Jake离开的时候,是他帮了我
He helped me out when Jake left.
你以前就认识他了,是不是?
You knew him before,though,right?
- 我们能不能说点儿别的? - 随你便
- Can we talk about something else? - Lf you want.
那么
What about...
你和我怎么样?
What about you and me?
我们怎么样?
What about us?
我并不了解你
I don't know about you,okay...
但我今天过得很开心
but I really enjoyed today.
是的,很开心
Yeah,it was fun.
我有种感觉,你想和我在一起
I just got the feeling that you wanted to be with me.
你知道,我喜欢你
You know I like you.
等等,伙计
Down,boy.
我知道你也喜欢我
I know you like me,too.
我承认 当你不那么讨厌的时候
I must say,when you're not being obnoxious...
你真的很讨人喜欢
you can be really quite sweet.
所以?
So?
- 你怎么想? - 对不起,我不能
- How was it for you? - Sorry.I can't.
- 什么叫你不能? - 好吧,我不想!
- What do you mean,you can't? - All right.I won't!
我曾经跟你讲过 我不跟在一起工作的人搞不清楚
I told you once before,I don't screw people I work with.
所有人?还是只有我?
People?Or is it just me?
什么让他这么特别了?
What makes him so special?
- 怎么回事? - 没什么
- What's going on? - Nothing.
- Danny? - 别问我
- Danny? - Don't ask me.
我只是机动人员
I'm just floating.
有人要见你
Someone to see you.
Albert Stroller
Albert Stroller.
Victor Maher
Victor Maher.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
是啊
It certainly has.
你看上去不错 是么,谢谢
- You're looking well. - Why,thank you.
你看上去混的不错
You look as though you're doing pretty well yourself.
你去见Maher了.他给了我这个
You went to see Maher.He sent me this.
他录了下来,我倒不知道
He taped it.I didn't see that coming.
你求他离我远点
You begged him to leave me alone.
我没有求他,我要求他
I didn't beg him,I asked.
你凭什么觉得我需要你或其他人的保护?
What makes you think I need yours or anyone else's protection?
你根本没有意识到,你将陷入什么局面
You've no idea what you're getting into.
- 我在使Danny免除牢狱之灾 - 而你却正在把你自己迁进去
- I'm keeping Danny out of prison. - You're putting yourself back in.
- 什么? - 坐下来
- What? - Sit down.
收起你的骄傲,坐下
Swallow your pride and sit down.
现在,好好想想
Now think.
是的,我当然会
Yes,of course I am.
不,先生 我明白了,先生
No,sir.I understand,sir.
Richards使Maher的银行遭殃
Richards has been plaguing Maher's bank.
他袭击了四个城市的分部
He's hit branches in four other cities.
根本没法抓住他
They haven't even come close to catching him.
这令他疯狂
It's driving him mad.
他跟他以前部门里的老朋友出去喝酒
He goes for a beer with some of his old friends from the Fraud Squad...
而他充耳所闻的都是你
and all he hears about is you.
他要你来抓住Richards
He set you up to catch Richards.
为什么?
Why?
来证明他自己
To prove he can.
又自大了
There's that ego again.
他让我来抓Richards
He set me up to catch Richards...
是要我们在同一个地方
to put us in the same place.
他为什么要这么干?
And why would he do that?
为了
To...
告诉我你没有（打算跟他在一块）
Please tell me you haven't.
我要跟Sam一块进保险箱
I'm going into the vault with Sam.
- 因为? - 他的父亲
- Because? - His father...
说来话长
It's a long story.
我相信那儿有个受伤滴血的心灵
I'm sure there's a bleeding heart in there somewhere.
而且我肯定Maher知道你会这么干
And I guarantee that Maher knew that's what you'd do.
我这么容易看透?
Am I that predictable?
他利用了你弱点
He plays to your weaknesses.
他让你们两个身处一块儿
He gets you both in the same place...
断了你们的后路 然后他就报警
he leaves you no way out,then he calls the police.
然后他得到他想要的
Then he gets what he desires most.
胜过Mickey Bricks
To be the man who outsmarted Mickey Bricks.
Danny不用进牢里,而你进去了
Danny stays out of prison and you go down instead.
你告诉我总归有办法的
You taught me there was always a way out.
因为我从来没有想到你会中Victor Maher的奸计
Because I never thought you'd run into Victor Maher.
他诱导你进这个游戏 耍得你团团转
He lures you into the game,plays you like a violin.
他找的每个骗子都犯了同一个错误
Every grifter he's sent away made the same mistake:
他们都觉得自己比他有心计
They all thought that they could outthink him.
但他们没有
But they couldn't.
我把你当儿子看待
I love you like a son...
但我也不觉得你斗得过他
but I don't think you could,either.
- 你要玩吗? - 不,我要赢
- You want to play? - No,I want to win.
我放弃
I give up.
帮帮我?
Help me?
好吧
Okay.
什么令你坚强?
What makes you strong?
我所知道的和你所教我的
What I know,what you taught me.
这不够
That's not enough.
他打败了我,记得吗?
He beat me,remember?
其他人
The others.
他们怎么想?
And where are they?
Ash一无所知,在问为什么
Ash doesn't know anything,wonders why.
他认为你不信任他
He thinks you don't trust him.
Stacie非常聪明
Stacie's bright as a button...
是你最忠实的队友
the best ally you've ever had.
你有问过她的意见吗
Have you asked her advice?
还有Danny的骗术天分 有一天甚至于超过你
And Danny's grift sense could put even you in the shade one day.
你有没有重用过他?
Have you used him?
没有,为什么不?
No.And why not?
因为你太骄傲了,开不了口
Because you're too proud to ask.
你觉得,全世界只要你一肩扛起就好了
You think the whole world is better off resting on your shoulders.
你很聪明
You've got a good brain.
好好想想
Use it.
你俩怎么不说话了?
You two not talking,then?
他不可理喻
He's impossible.
所以你是因为他是Danny而生他的气?
So you're angry with Danny for being Danny?
对不起
I'm sorry.
没什么的
Don't worry about it.
说真的
I mean it.
我今天真的很开心
And I really did enjoy today.
Stacie,Mickey找你
Stacie,Mickey wants you.
所以你全知道,而把我蒙在鼓里?
So you knew all this and never said a word to me?
是我不对Danny.对不起
That was wrong,Danny.I'm sorry.
现在你们都知道了 我们是最强的团队
And that goes for all of you.We're strongest as a team.
而我却忘记了
I tend to forget that.
所以,如果你不搞定这个人 Danny就要进监狱
So if you don't set this guy up,Danny goes to prison.
而如果你做了,你就要进监狱?
And if you do,you go instead?
就是这样
That's about it.
这真是笔好买卖
That's a good deal.
我们现在是不是都漏了重点?
Aren't we all missing the point now?
- 什么? - 我走,问题就解决了
- Which is? - Lf I go away,so does the problem.
这不是选择
That's not an option.
出于整个家族 三个火枪手的故事
Because of the whole family,musketeer thing.
听着,我是新人,我会让你摆脱这个
Listen,I'm the new kid.I'll let you off that.
不,因为那意味着他击败了我们
No,because it means he'll have beaten us.
一直到那家伙打开保险箱,你才能拿到带子?
You don't get the tape till this guy's opened the vault?
是的
Right.
而少任何一个,保险箱都打不开
And he can't open the vault without one of us.
没错
Right,too.
一定程度上,你俩拴在一个绳子上
At which point you both get a tug.
我不觉得我们有胜算
I don't see how we can win.
如果我们进去了 你能不能从别的路走?
If we get you inside,can we get you out another way?
不行,原路进去,原路返回
No,there's one way in,one way out.
就像那个
It's like one of them things.
三个笨蛋花4个小时挖一个洞
It takes three blokes four hours to dig a hole.
如果6个人挖一个小点的洞要多久?
How long does it take six men to dig a smaller hole?
算了吧Danny
Shut up,Danny.
问题是,我们有没有其他主意?
The question is,do we have any ideas?
我从来没这么高兴过
I don't think I've ever had so much fun.
我很高兴我能帮上忙
I'm glad to have been of service.
一直到胖女人唱歌,才会结束
It ain't all over till the fat lady sings.
你打击我要我放弃吗
Don't you disappoint me by giving up.
你给我的选择太苛刻
The options you've left me are rather limited.
我没有给你任何选择
I haven't left you any options.
就这么回事
That's how this thing works.
那么,什么时候?
So,when?
- 今晚 - 怎么做?
- Tonight. - How?
他会黑入主机 然后改变视网膜扫描
He's hacking into the mainframe and resetting the retina scans.
很聪明
Clever.
但有个问题
But there's a problem.
- 这要两个人 - 不
- It takes two people. - No.
你做什么?
What are you going to do?
我和他一起进去
I'm going in with him.
但你早就知道了,是不是?
But you already knew that,didn't you?
这好像是逻辑问题
Seemed like the logical thing.
Albert会在场,把带子交给他
Albert will be there.Give him the tape.
当我看到你的脸出现在sam边上 而且保险箱打开的时候
When I see your face next to Sam's,and the vault door open.
看着警报在你们周围响一定很有意思
It's been a pleasure running rings round you.
银行
The bank.
Stacie,你和Danny 进行第一阶段
Stacie,you and Danny go and set up the first phase.
我们需要见这里的老板
We'd like to see the manager,please.
我能问问这个连接什么的?
Can I ask what it's in connection with?
警察
Police.
接下来Albert
Albert next.
他们知道他是谁 所以我们需要一个掩护
They know who he is,so we'll need a disguise.
Peregrin B.Winterhill三世,我想
Peregrin B.Winterhill III,I think.
很好
Perfect.
这个提供机会让我和sam进去
That should provide enough of a diversion for me and Sam to get in.
我去拿东西,到那儿碰头,Danny
I'll pick up the materials and meet you there,Danny.
你能准备份礼物吗?
Can you sort out the present?
好了,干吧
Okay,let's do it.
哦,我的天哪 我太尴尬了,你知道
Oh,my God,I'm so embarrassed,you know.
对不起,我弯不下来
I'm sorry,I can't bend over.
好了,第二步
Right,phase two.
有两个门 Mickey搞定锁
Two gates at the side.Mickey will take care of the locks.
会把你引向这扇门
Which will bring you to this door.
到那时,Albert会去见Maher
By that time,Albert will just be arriving to meet Maher.
这时候,所有人都要就位
You guys should be in position by this time.
如果Maher真的如Albert所说的那么聪明 他很快就会发现
If Maher's as smart as Albert says he is,it won't take him long to figure it out.
这样一来,他就会行动
From this point,he'll be running.
你有三分半钟
That will give you three and a half minutes.
行不行?
All right?
我们知道他们会进来 我们什么没有办法
We know they'll be coming in,nothing we can do about that.
所以他们会从这个方向出去 你明白我的意思吗?
So they'll be using this direction to get out.You understand me?
这个方向,所以你们给我看好
This direction,so you stay alert.
我们要抢先一步
We'll be one step ahead.
准备好了吗?
You ready?
Albert来得正是时候
Albert,just in time for the show.
他们进去了,切换到保险箱里的摄像头
They're in.Switch to the vault cameras.
- 让你的人各就各位 - 是的,先生
- Get your men in position.- Yes,sir.
这肯定让你很难堪,Albert
This must be very galling for you,Albert...
看着你的人倒霉?
watching the downfall of your protg?
抓到了
Gotcha.
就是这个,来吧
That's the one.Come on.
他们在保险箱里 关上外面的门,我这就下来
They're in the vault.Seal the outer door.I'm coming down.
要不要跟我一块,Albert?
Care to join me,Albert?
见证我辉煌的时刻
Watch my moment of glory.
把带子给我
Just give me the tape.
说"请"
Say "please."
请
Please.
先生
Sir.
有烟,重复,有烟 带上毒气面罩
Smoke.I repeat,smoke.Get the gas masks.
打开它
Unlock it.
他们不可能进去的,先生
They won't get through,sir.
烟在哪里?我闻到烟味
Where's the smoke?I smell smoke.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
安全系统被绕过了
Security override.
行动!
Move!
让开!
Move out of the way!
他们重新安装过电路了,该死.
They've rerouted it.Oh,shit.
快点!
Come on,quickly!
他们肯定把它改到隔壁的门去了
They must have routed it next door.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
那儿是什么?
What's in there?
你不能进去 是警局的监视
You can't go in there.It's police surveillance.
快,回到保险库
Quick,back to the vault.
很奇怪能在这里见到你
Fancy meeting you here.
2分钟
Two minutes.
找到了
Got it.
- 走吧 - 你开玩笑?
- Let's go. - You are joking?
我们不是小偷,Danny
We're not thieves,Danny.
听着,为你自己着想一下 我是全能
Listen,speak for yourself.I'm very versatile.
Mickey说拿了钻石就走
Mickey said to take the diamond and go.
- Mickey说 - Danny
- Mickey says... - Danny.
走吧
Let's go.
他怎么了?
What's up with him?
他只是要碰到私人危机了
He's just having a personal crisis.
那儿有上百万镑
It's got millions in there.
Milk的火车半小时离开
Milk train leaves in half an hour.
- 我不知道该怎么谢你 - 那就不用谢了
- I don't know how to thank you. - Then don't.
你真的帮了我大忙
You actually did me a favor.
- 真的? - 我了解了自己很多
- Really? - I learnt a lot about myself.
什么是重要的
What's important.
我父亲对我来说是很重要的
My dad was important to me.
我也是
Mine,too.
你保重
You take care.
哦,干得非常漂亮,不是吗?
Well,that went rather well,right?
就像有人说的
Like the man said:
直到胖女人唱歌,它才停止
It ain't over till the fat lady sings.
这提醒了我
Which reminds me.
什么?
Yes?
干得好,Victor,但是没有雪茄
Nice try,Victor,but no cigar.
但既然我这么享受这个游戏
But as I enjoyed playing the game so much...
我们准备了份小礼物给你
we've arranged a little present for you...
如果你往你办公室窗外看
if you'd like to look out of your office window...
我们好朋友Albert Stroller的一点心意
courtesy of our friend,Mr.Albert Stroller.
- 我真想看看他现在的表情 - 我也是
- I'd love to have seen his face. - Me,too.
是的,在办公室里
Right,in the office.
我去睡觉了,累死了
I'll turn in.I'm absolutely knackered.
什么?
What?
- 他有没有一刻是单独待在保险库里的? - 等等
- Was he left alone in the vault at any time? - Now,wait a minute.
他忘了拿象棋,不得不折回
He forgot to leave the chess piece,had to go back.
- 我什么也没干 - 哦,亲爱的
- I didn't do anything. - Oh,dear.
Danny,你有什么要告诉我们的吗?
Danny,is there anything you'd like to tell us?
- 你说什么呢? - 要我来搜身吗?
- What're you talking about? - Want me to frisk him?
我什么也没干
I haven't done anything.
好,那你不介意解了你的夹克吧
Good,then you won't mind unbuttoning your jacket.
- 你们不信我? - 解了它
- You don't trust me? - Unbutton.
继续,给我们看看
Go on,show us.
这简直难以置信,我有...
That is unbelievable.What have I ever got...
- 转身 - 冷静点
- Turn around. - Go easy.
好了,做你想做的
All right,do what you want.
等等,你居然没拿钱?
Hold on,you didn't take any money?
不,我没有,伙计.但你知道吗?
No,I didn't,mate.But you know what?
你们这么想我感到很吃惊,也有点生气
I'm shocked and a little bit upset that you thought that I did.
谢谢,伙计们
Thanks,guys.
好吧,那就由我来吧
Well,just must have been me then.
你?
You?
- 酬劳 - 你是小偷
- Expenses. - You're the thief.
一人一叠
One each.
除了
Except...
我有两叠
I've got two.
小偷
Thief.
- 50便士 - 给你
- 50 pence. - There you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
等等,这是你余下的找头
Hang on,the rest of your change.
对不起
Sorry.
4个五便士,还有五个10便士
Four makes five and five's 10.
我有1个的硬币 我有零钱,你把刚刚那个还我,Eddie?
I've got a 1 coin.Give me my 10 back,will you,Eddie?
我该给你5便士和5个硬币
I'll give you 5 and five 1.
帮我兑了这个零钱
Help me lose this change.
最好看看
Better check it.
- 等等,这里只有9个 - 对不起
- Hang on,there's only 9 here. - Sorry.
- 你那儿有多少? - 9个
- What have you got there? - 9.
我给你11 你给我20
I'll give you 11,you give me 20.
好了
All right.
谢谢
Thanks.
等等 你在那儿开心什么?
Wait a minute.Did you do something funny there?
没什么
Of course not.